<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><ARTICLE><TITLE>Editor’s Desk</TITLE><SUBTITLE> </SUBTITLE><AUTHOR> </AUTHOR><SNIPPET>&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
Persecution is not a new feature to Christendom. It’s been there since ages and the Church had lived with it through. What surprises the historians and the persecutors alike is, the more the Church was persecuted the more Church grew in numbers turning even the nations into Christian nations. Many tried their wit, wisdom, whip and even weaponry but the Church had outlived its persecutors.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</SNIPPET><IMAGE>editor.jpg</IMAGE><FULL>&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt; 
Persecution is not a new feature to Christendom. It’s been there since ages and the Church had lived with it through. What surprises the historians and the persecutors alike is, the more the Church was persecuted the more Church grew in numbers turning even the nations into Christian nations. Many tried their wit, wisdom, whip and even weaponry but the Church had outlived its persecutors.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 Subash Chouhan of Bajrang Dal once said, In the country, Orissa is the second (to Gujarat) Hindu Rajya. (Hindu kingdom or State). It could be and we all agree. But times change. History repeats. Remember Nagas in India. They were the deadliest people in the country known as the head hunters. It was not civilization or the government that changed them. It was the Gospel of Jesus that converted them and transformed their lives. Come to grips with this, in the light of these and millions of lives that are transformed, is conversion wrong?
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
It is simple wisdom, man cannot fight God, it is natural science Christ taught that when a grain of wheat falls to the ground and dies, it brings life. While Gujarat is boasted as the first ’Hindu Rajya’ it should not be mentioned with this that India's first and all Christians village (100%)is in Gujarat. (Read FoL March – April 2008 p. 6)
Today is tomorrow's history. Those of us now watching these atrocities on Christians in Orissa, would one day testify of the story of the grains that fell to the ground in Orissa. If our breath does not hold us so long to live, the pages of history would read for them of the story of the grains that fell to the ground in Orissa. If historians twist the truth and influence the pen and the page...may it be written in the blue sky above us for the world all over to read of the story of the grains that fell to the ground in Orissa.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
Please uphold these families in your prayers
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
With Prayers and Blessings,
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
Sunny Joseph Mylabathula&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</FULL></ARTICLE>