<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ARTICLE>
<TITLE>1000 + 1000 = 2</TITLE>
<SUBTITLE>Math of Another Kind</SUBTITLE>
<AUTHOR>Sunny Joseph</AUTHOR>
<SNIPPET>One day, is that not enough for you...one day we were born, one day we shall die, the same day, the same second, is that not enough for you? They give birth astride of a grave, the light gleams an instant, then it’s night once more.”&lt;br&gt;~ Samuel Beckett,&lt;br&gt;Waiting for Godot</SNIPPET>

<IMAGE>x.jpg</IMAGE>

<FULL>&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;br&gt;We all have heard the catchphrase ‘think outside the box.’ WWhile this management concept became instantly famous, this could be a distracter to Christians. I would say, ‘think from inside The Book’ which is the Bible and that itself would ensure results like or more like ‘outside the box’ results. The metaphor outside the box means to think differently, unconventionally, or from a new perspective. What could be anything newer than what Solomon who already instructed, “What has been will be again, what has been done will be done again; there is nothing new under the sun. Is there anything of which one can say, “Look! This is something new”? It was here already, long agrememo; it was here before our time. No one remembers the former generations, and even those yet to come will not be remembered by those who follow them.” [Eccl. 1:9-11]&lt;br&gt;Further, John Wright writes, “We live in Dark Ages. Do not be deceived by our technological marvels. The era after the fall of Rome in the Western lands of Europe was also an age of unparalleled technical advancement, from eyeglasses to clockworks to horse collars to wheelbarrows to stirrups. What makes this age Dark is not merely contempt for reason, but an inability of the educated classes to reason coherently when called upon to do so. A man who thinks he can reinvent his own human nature by an act of will is a man who, ultimately, does not believe that truth is true.” This is exactly what the Bible says.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;Before we embark on reading this rather ambiguous article, may I caution you that the content you are about to read is a meat only for the strong to eat. Thus said, let me take you into the journey I myself have embarked on, a few decades ago but only realised in the recent past how different, difficult and distant my understanding of the journey was.&lt;br&gt;When man embarks on a journey beginning from the womb [for it is from there we all must make our entry into this world] we more often believe than less understand that we are here forever. While the notion is partly true, it is also partly a lie. For, from the moment we are delivered into this world, we live daily inch by inch in a close proximity to the tomb. Some realise this but many ignore it, reasons being fear of such a thought or mere ignorance. Though the truth of the ignorance is beautiful, we are not exempted from the realities of death hanging over our lives constantly; day in and day out.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;Hebrew Wisdom:&lt;br&gt;In Moses’ prayer in Psalm 90 we see a vivid picture of man’s days on the earth. It chills to read when it comes to verse 4, “For a thousand years in thy sight are but as yesterday when it is past, and as a watch in the night.” In God’s time frame, imagine that the past two millennia of world history are to God as just two days. So when our 2,000 years are but two days to God, calculate the 70-80 years of human life on earth. The Hebrew word for ‘flourisheth’ in v.6 is tsoots; meaning, a twinkle. This is more shocking for those who theorise, ‘we are here forever.’ I was one among the many who believed we are here forever. But it is not. If our life is a twinkle on this earth true wisdom must hasten us to relive our lives constantly repairing and preparing to face the end of it.&lt;br&gt;The safest place in the world is the womb, so it is considered, yet, death can peek in even there to find its next victim, and much more, after life comes into this world. Let us be generous and give us humans a life span of 70-80 years. It is a long period, but if it gets snuffed earlier before that period, no complains please. Max Mueller says, “...however short they [years] may have been, were only given to us, we do not deserve them.” Given such an ample life span of 70-80 years, against some of the world’s greatest men who lived less than half this period, have made it to the greatest of heights hitting the very zenith of the fields they are known for. I am thinking of Paschal, John Keats, Percy Bysshe Shelley, Alexander the Great [nicknamed the King of Babylon, King of Asia King of the Four Quarters of the World] and of late Paul Walker. Of course, Jesus of Nazareth is a different case. Now consider those who lived longer a life than those mentioned above who achieved what they achieved. Julius Caesar, Caesar Augustus, Akbar the Great, Queen Victoria, Adolf Hitler, Lenin, Karl Marx and the list&lt;br&gt;can go on. What they achieved, had not their glory ultimately led them to the grave? Ultimately letting everything they earned and achieved passed on to the next in line. Does this ring a bell? King Solomon realised this when he wrote, “...because I should leave it unto the man that shall be after me.” Eccl. 2:18. King Solomon captures brilliantly the life and works of us humans in his writings, “For there is no remembrance of the wise more than of the fool for ever; seeing that which now is in the days to come shall all be forgotten. And how dieth the wise man? as the fool.” Eccl. 2:16.&lt;br&gt;Hebrew wisdom teaches about different dead- ends in human pursuit and it would do us good to consider some of them in the lives of some spectacular and the most colourful of men and women who lived in the past. Call it from history, but I would, from the book of the dead.&lt;br&gt;The Four Deadly Dead Ends Dead End # 1. Pursuit of Wisdom&lt;br&gt;And I gave my heart to know wisdom, and to know madness and folly: I perceived that this also is vexation of spirit. For in much wisdom is much grief: and he that increaseth knowledge increaseth sorrow. King Solomon&lt;br&gt;Eccl. 1:17,18&lt;br&gt;Leonard Ravenhill once wrote about the founder of a leading Christian magazine in the&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;US who “...sent out a questionnaire to what he called, ‘Twenty of the leading intellectual preachers in the country.’ ” Ravenhill continues, “...Those men who turned the world upside down had, had no colossal intellectual capacity. No great financial backing. No social standing. They were about the most despised men in and around Jerusalem. And yet they broke out somehow – and later it was said that they turned the world upside down.” Ravenheill’s question seems to be, what intellectuals are we talking about and who decides and with what measure scale is applied.&lt;br&gt;Unlike the Greek concept of wisdom which is more intellectual and acquisition of knowledge, the Hebrew idea of wisdom is more about walking rather than thinking or talking.&lt;br&gt;The Hebrew word for ‘wisdom’ is chokmah which literally means ‘skilful.’ The Hebrew concept of wisdom is more about living beyond intellectual pursuit to the practical, hands-on ability to live one’s daily life successfully, applying knowledge in concrete ways. Wisdom in Hebrew mindset includes the ideas of good sense, aptitude and technical skill on life and issue’s of life. In simple words, Hebrew concept of wisdom is practical, while the Greek idea of wisdom is theoretical. Sophia which is the Greek word for wisdom is a central idea in Hellenistic philosophy and religion. More synonyms like intelligence, insight, wit etc., are the words associated with the Greek concept of wisdom or Sophia.&lt;br&gt;Hebrew or Biblical wisdom speaks of Spirit of God’s wisdom which is based on the application of skill understanding and knowledge revealed by God, “And I have filled him with the spirit of God, in wisdom, and in understanding, and in knowledge...” [Ex. 32:3]. The ground rule here is, the wise hear and are instructed by God’s Spirit to apply knowledge which is for practical purpose&lt;br&gt;of living, for all wisdom is found in God alone, “With him [God] is wisdom and strength, he hath counsel and understanding.” [Job 12:13]&lt;br&gt;The foundations of wisdom are fear of God and the Word of God which Solomon overlooked. He broke the instruction of God’s Word when he multiplied his wives, brought horses from Egypt and built altar for strange gods. These are just a few instances; he lived a life denying God and His Word.&lt;br&gt;When Solomon began to write Ecclesiastes he was still the king over Israel but by the time he came to chapter 1 and verse 12, he was no more the king of Israel for he writes, “I the Preacher was king over Israel in Jerusalem.” By this time, the preacher turned king has understood the value and the worth of wisdom.&lt;br&gt;If Solomon was a wise man, why does he write, “in much wisdom is much grief: and he that increaseth knowledge increaseth sorrow.” Solomon started off well with God, but as he progressed, he drifted and intermingled his wisdom with the wisdom of the world which James talks about, “the wisdom which descends not from above but from the earth, sensual and devilish.” [Jas 3:15]&lt;br&gt;Dead End # 2. Pursuit of Wealth&lt;br&gt;Humans are at peace when there is financial security and sleep well with little or no fear when there is money in the chests both for present and future needs. It was Christopher Morley who said, “There are three ingredients in the good life: learning, earning and yearning. Even the Bible exhorts in Proverbs 12:11, “Whoever works his land will have plenty of bread...” King Solomon knew it well and made it big when he earned great wealth. Apart from what he inherited from his father King David, Solomon prospered and grew richer through commerce, trading, gifts he received, tribute money paid to him and the taxes he collected. Cool, he was wise and applied his wisdom in all fields and multiplied his investments. It is estimated that he received each year, “...between $1,092,906,000 and $1,165,766,400 U.S. dollars!.” Solomon became so immensely rich that all his cups were made of gold [not one was made of silver. 1Kings 10:21]. His wealth was so immense that gold and silver were as common in Jerusalem as stones (2Chronicles 1:15, see also 1Kings 10:27)! The Bible tells that God promised him riches making him the all time wealthiest man, “...I will give thee riches, and wealth, and honour, such as none of the kings have had that have been before thee, neither shall there any after thee have the like.” [2Ch 1:12]&lt;br&gt;It is said that his wealth by today’s standards would dwarf the present day billionaires. However, the dangers of such pursuit is further warned, “Do not toil to acquire wealth; be discerning enough to desist.” Proverbs 23:4 [ESV]. Looking at his wealth he also said, “Then I looked on all the works that my hands had wrought, and on the labour that I had laboured to do: and, behold, all was vanity and vexation of spirit, and there was no profit under the sun.” What a dead end of a pursuit we all human pursue desperately. Consider the dead end of what Solomon reached and vexed in his spirit.&lt;br&gt;How Rich are You?&lt;br&gt;Before we answer the question, ‘How rich you are,’ let us ask ourselves, how do we measure our wealth? Is it the land value of our houses, our jobs, businesses, bank balance or our net worth? Compared to the rich by the standards of the world, it would insult us to sit and evaluate our worth. Markets change, fortunes fail making princes into paupers instantly. Well, taken for granted you are rich and are listed in the Forbes, financial riches alone do not matter in life, there are other sides to it like the social, medical, health, moral and spiritual. Where do we standard?&lt;br&gt;Izaak Walton a 16th century English writer author of The Compleat Angler, writes, “There may be many that have forty times our estates...[but we with] a little money have eat and drunk, and laughed...and sung and slept, securely; and rose next day, and cast away care, and sung, and laughed...which are blessings rich men cannot purchase with all their money...I have a rich neighbour that is always so busy but he has no leisure to laugh; the whole business of his life is to get money, and more money, that he may still get more and more money; and he is still drudging on...Let us therefore be, be thankful...above all a quite conscience.”&lt;br&gt;God wants us to prosper [but] we need to find the balance. The Bible tells, “Every man also to whom God hath given&lt;br&gt;riches and wealth, and hath given him power to eat thereof, and to take his portion, and to rejoice in his labour; this is the gift of God,” Eccl. 5:19. And it is He who gives power to multiply our wealth. [Deut 18:8] and when God gives wealth He adds no sorrow to it. [Prov.10:22] Can we consider why Solomon the all time wealthiest man’s wealth drove him to sorrow and emptiness? God was faithful in what he promised in blessing Solomon with all the riches and wealth but Solomon was not. He put God outside his life.&lt;br&gt;Dead End # 3. Pursuit of Power&lt;br&gt;Growing up as a child I never understood why the great Julius Caesar was assassinated by his own men. Caesar’s most emotional utterance, ‘et Brutus’ [you too Brutus] got etched in my memory. In my mind Caesar was a hero and Brutus a villain. As a student of literature, I fought trying not to think of Caesar as a villain but to my surprise, he was. Reading through Roman history one will realise that Gius Julius Caesar wooed his people with speeches like, “I want to see Rome boundless, united and free.” Mark Antony’s emotional speech to the Roman citizens, “Caesar loves his own life less than he loves Romans,” made Caesar a darling of Rome. However, Caesar betrayed Rome by suppressing their freedom and declared himself a dictator. The irony is, when he was assassinated, people cried out, “Freedom, liberty, peace.” In the words of Edward Gibbon, “...a quarrel between two generals, Caesar and Pompey, [for power] brought the fall of the Republic.” What was Caesar’s crime? Love of power. The very power that Caesar loved and worshipped killed him. Who can down play the Roman era and the glory of it? The only world empire that ruled for more than 500 years [44 BC – 476 BC] and lived for more than a 1,000 years on history’s pages, but lies now in ruins. CH. Spurgeon writes, “Go to Palestine and see how the Caesars are forgotten of the halls which echoed to their despotic mandates, and resounded with the plaudits of the nations over which they ruled...”&lt;br&gt;Think of Adolf Hitler who thought his Nazism would rule the world for centuries, likewise, Saddam Hussein, who claimed himself the heir to King Nebuchadnezzar and wanted to bring back the Babylonian glory in the modern day Iraq. He moved every stone in pursuit of this golden dream to restore and rebuild the golden age of Babylon. “Under President Saddam Hussein one of the ancient world’s most legendary cities has begun to rise again...the new Babylon is self-consciously dedicated to the idea that Nebuchadnezzar has a successor in Mr. Hussein, whose military prowess and vision will restore to Iraqis the glory their ancestors knew when all of what is now Iraq, Syria, Lebanon, Jordan, Kuwait and Israel was under Babylonian control.” [The New York Times, International, October 11,1990] The list can go on with more names, but the end of them all was, they all have risen to heights unimaginable in one life time, but they all fell to the dust in a lightening quick fall.&lt;br&gt;Dead End # 4. Pursuit of Pleasure&lt;br&gt;Pleasure is a freedom-song,&lt;br&gt;But it is not freedom.&lt;br&gt;It is the blossoming of your desires,&lt;br&gt;But it is not their fruit...&lt;br&gt;Ay, in very truth, pleasure is a freedom song. And I fain would have you sing it&lt;br&gt;with fullness of heart;&lt;br&gt;yet I would not have you&lt;br&gt;lose your hearts in the singing. ~Kahlil Gibran&lt;br&gt;On Pleasure&lt;br&gt;“He that loves pleasure must for pleasure fall.” ~ Christopher Marlowe, Doctor Faustus&lt;br&gt;Pleasure is beautiful and is worth pursuing. However, it comes with a caution, ‘conditions apply.’ The laws of pleasure be it for extreme or limited pleasure must be applied before one takes a dip to sip it. First law of pleasure is the law of time [age] and place. Second, law of ownership and finally, law of legal and moral standards.&lt;br&gt;To Solomon, none of these rules applied when he indulged in what his heart desired, “And whatsoever mine eyes desired I kept not from them, I withheld not my heart from any joy...”[Eccl. 2:10] He had no notion what and how his first wife and the subsequent wives felt when he went on a marriage spree taking one wife after another. He regarded not the scriptures, “Neither shall he multiply wives to himself that his heart turns not away...” [Deut. 17:17]. Forget how Solomon’s first wife felt when he took his second wife, in the very first place he had no qualms even to God who instructed against marrying outside Israel [Deut.7: 3]. Though Solomon’s age and political position as a king gave him eligibility to marry, the marital standard according to God’s law was, “one wife for one man.”&lt;br&gt;In psychology, the pleasure principle describes pleasure as a positive feedback mechanism, motivating the organism to recreate in the future the situation which it has just found pleasurable. According to this theory, organisms are similarly motivated to avoid situations that have caused pain in the past. Recreational drug use can be pleasurable: some drugs, illicit and otherwise, directly create euphoria in the human brain when ingested. The mind’s natural tendency to seek out more of this feeling [as described by the principle of pleasure ] can lead to dependence and addiction. Solomon’s condition in this matter was what Søren Kierkegaard said, “Many of us pursue pleasure with such breathless haste that we hurry past it.”&lt;br&gt;Pleasure satisfies the desires creating euphoria in the human brain when enjoyed. The natural result of such euphoria is to seek more which from gradually or steadily increases in frequency asking for more and higher dosage depending on the pleasure one seeks. If unstopped, this pursuit of pleasure takes one on a roller coaster speed. One life is sufficient to lure, woo and wed one woman and later to care and to keep her content for the rest of the life. That is what the Creator’s intent was when He created the first man and woman. Think of Solomon who had a 1,000 woman whom he took in his life time. The Rabbis say that Solomon lived 52 years. This means he lived 18, 980 days [52x365] and had one woman for every 19 days [18,980 ÷1,000] approximately 1,000 woman. Can we call it an unbridled lust for pleasure or foolishness? Rene Descartes writes, “The greatest minds are capable of the greatest vices as well as of the greatest virtues.” Solomon rightly fits into this category of greatest minds.&lt;br&gt;Vanity vs Virtue&lt;br&gt;The pursuit of wisdom, wealth, power and pleasure is not bad. God wants us to enjoy the fullness of them but there are boundaries set to each one of these so none needs to be a dead end but one perpetual and a beautiful experience. We become what we sow and we are what we produce.&lt;br&gt;A transformed fool is often wiser than the wisest for he has to his merit mistakes he made, if not how then would have Solomon who experienced all what he experienced could say, ‘Vanity of vanities.’ He surely must have realised the folly of having a 1,000 women in his life. Did we not read that behind every successful man is a woman and behind every unsuccessful man there are two? If this is true, behind every wise man there must be 3 or more wives and Solomon is an example who surpassed all those numbers. Solomon was a very wise man before he foolishly applied God’s wisdom and dashed full throttle on the wrong side of wisdom. After such a foolish trip, good heavens, his wisdom roared, ‘vanity...vanity...vanities...all is vanity.’&lt;br&gt;There is good news for both Solomon and such like Solomon. God’ grace is abundant for the home comers. He does this to all, but the condition is back to the Bible. Human nature inspires to indulge but divine wisdom compels us to return. Consider Henry David Thoreau, in Walden, “If you have built castles in the air, your work need not be lost; that is where they should be. Now put the foundations under them.” Foundations comes first, but if in your folly, you forgot to lay them down, get wise and built them NOW, at least. This is wisdom, though late, but not never.&lt;br&gt;Conclusion&lt;br&gt;When we rival God and His purpose for the universe in those few fleeting moments of our 70 years which is for God like a night watch and a twinkle in the eternity of God’s time frame we fail to live purposefully. A Jewish interpretation of Ps.90: 12 says, “According to the count of our days so make known, then we shall acquire a heart of wisdom.” The word ”So...” is translated from a Hebrew term pronounced, “kane,” which has a numerical value of 70 and compares to the previous teaching in verse 10 that our live has an average span of 70 years&lt;br&gt;The expression, “so that we may attain a heart of wisdom,” is navi levav chochmah in the original Hebrew and the term ‘attain’ here has the same root as the term for prophet. Rabbi Abraham Isaac Kook suggested that we might therefore read this phrase, “Teach us to number our days — as a prophet [with] a heart of wisdom.” Reading the Psalm this way, we see that living our lives fully and meaningfully, so that our short lives have enduring significance, means living with the awareness of God’s divine purpose in mind. We would not claim to be prophets.&lt;br&gt;To this day some Jewish customs frown on counting people, “Cattle are counted, people are not counted,” but the number of days they are taught.&lt;br&gt;In conclusion, let us remind ourselves that if our 1000 years are just one day for God, what our 70 years are. Hebrew wisdom says, it is like a twinkle. This is God’s math.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</FULL></ARTICLE>