<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ARTICLE>
<TITLE>Jonty Rhodes (Jonathan Neil Rhodes)</TITLE>
<SUBTITLE>South African - Cricket Player</SUBTITLE>
<AUTHOR>Sunil Roberts</AUTHOR>
<SNIPPET>&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
It was the gusty display of quick feet and hands of jonty, that made hims a permanent fixture in the South Africa’s Cricket team. Jonty went on to startle the world of cricket with his hard-to-catch on the camer feate and presented to the world a new dimension in fieldingand catching. .  The middle son of prayerful parents, both teachers, Jonty grew with strict Christian discipline in the family which he carries even today, on the international cricket field and as one of South Africa’s finest hockey players.In a exclusive interview about his Christian faith, Jonty speaks to our ’Research Editor’ Sunil Robert in Hyderabad, India for Fountail of Life. The hotel was buzzing with activity. With TV crew, photographers and scribes looking for that exclusive interview with the elusive sports icons. Obviously if South Africa is part of the draw they tend to overshadow everyone, often the Indians with one exception though. The cricket team manager had announced an open session with the team.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</SNIPPET>
<IMAGE>Jonty.jpg</IMAGE>
<FULL>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;


It was the gusty display of quick feet and hands of jonty, that made hims a permanent fixture in the South Africa’s Cricket team. Jonty went on to startle the world of cricket with his hard-to-catch on the camer feate and presented to the world a new dimension in fieldingand catching. .  The middle son of prayerful parents, both teachers, Jonty grew with strict Christian discipline in the family which he carries even today, on the international cricket field and as one of South Africa’s finest hockey players.In a exclusive interview about his Christian faith, Jonty speaks to our ’Research Editor’ Sunil Robert in Hyderabad, India for Fountail of Life. The hotel was buzzing with activity. With TV crew, photographers and scribes looking for that exclusive interview with the elusive sports icons. Obviously if South Africa is part of the draw they tend to overshadow everyone, often the Indians with one exception though. The cricket team manager had announced an open session with the team.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 I wanted to spend time with Andrew Hudson the explosive opening batsman and of course the mercurial Jonty Rhodes who seems to have catapulted the entire discipline of fielding on to a new plane. Who can ever forget his bird-in-flight run-out of Inzaman Ul Haw in the 1992 World Cup in Australia. Jonathan Neil Rhodes better known to millions as Jonty has single handedly elevated the status of a fielder in a cricket team. Someone, who for many years stayed as a fielder, is known to be the quintessential team man, someone who can lift the spirits of the team. Chirpy, effusive and eternally restless Jonty is the same on, and off the field. Even when speaking to someone, his roving eyes tend to keep searching for that elusive something often coveying the impression that he is bored. When indicated that I would be interested in spending more time to know of his faith and belief in Christ, he willingly spent time sharing his love and devotion on his personal Savior and God Jesus Christ.

&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
Whether it’s plucking of catches bulleting past him or whether it is boyishly lifting people’s sagging spirits. Jonty Rhodes has the ability of making people sit up and notice. More Power to him.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;FoL : The world knows a lot of Jonty the cricketer, what is it to be Jonty, the believer? How did you come to know Christ?&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br&gt;
JONTY : I came to know the Lord in a personal manner through the efforts of my wife KATE. She was my fiancee and she was a deep believer. It was through her prayers and commitment that I was drawn to make a choice to accept Jesus into my life. After that, somehow God transformed every area of my life.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;FoL : What difference did conversion make in your life?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
JONTY : Earlier, when I played for Natal or anyother team, there was that pressure for me to perform all the time. But, once I gave my life to Christ it did not really matter whether I scored a century or took five catches or scored duck and didn’t take a catch. It was a shift in attitude that really took off the pressure. Earlier too, I would have gone to church every Sunday, but I did not have personal relationship with God. As a result, whenever I played well, I used to pat myself on the back and when success eluded me I used to feel depressed. I knew from KATE what was missing in my life. I gave my life to Christ in 1990. Now I feel that the talents God gave are not meant for personal success, but for the extension of God’s kingdom. Now, I ask myself it I am fulfilling the will of God rather than, asking myself have I played well or not?
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;FoL : Your reflexes are not to be quick and often compared to Colin Blands. What is the secret?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;

JONTY : I have never seen Colin Blands field, but I think he is better than me. I had this instinct for sports. All I ever wanted to do was play whether it meant playing hockey or running around with a cricket ball, God have me a personality that was cut out for sports. I practice hard to keep myself agile but to place things in perspective it’s as if God gave me a set of talents and I work hard to prove them useful.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;FoL : You are known to be a role model for young people around the world? Does that put pressure on you? &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
JONTY : No, on the contrary I enjoy doing what I am doing and to be able to relate to youth at their level. If I can encourage someone to do their best without getting into drugs and stuff like that, it is indeed satisfying.
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;FoL : How do you handle it when till recently you were dropped from the test team?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
JONTY : Prayer and the burning desire to do justice to my talent. Whenever I was dropped from the test side, I used to go back to NATAL and get huge scores and force my way back into the squad. Infact, once after I got a hundred, Dominic Cork told me that I was the most luckiest cricketer he ever met. Luck has nothing to do with it. I play with a straight bat and my practice partner Gary Kristen, is always impressed with the straight bat shots I play. I told Dominic that it is prayer that is the secret of my success.

&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"&gt;
 &lt;b&gt;FoL : What is life like after retirement from active cricket?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
JONTY : I am not sure. But I guess it will be definitely something to do with ministry using my past as a cricketer. I guess I’d like to go to young people and share the word of God and tell people about the real life in Jesus. At this stage I really have no clue as to what life will be afterwards. My wife KATE and me, we are praying and planning. Let’s see.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</FULL></ARTICLE>