<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
**************************************************************************
HOW TO EDIT FOL ARTICLE XML FILES:

- For all entries, text will be sufficient.
  However, to stylize the FULL, you must use HTML for line breaking
  
Escape Characters (ONLY COPY THE PART AFTER THE DASH):

< - &lt;
> - &gt;
" - &quot;

USE THIS IN PLACE OF ENTER - FOR LINE BREAKS
<br> - &lt;br&gt;
 

USE THIS BEFORE EVERY PARAGRAPH
<p><font face="Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif"> - &lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&quot; Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif&quot; &gt;
USE THEIS AFTER EVERY PARAGRAPH
</font></p> - &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

**************************************************************************
-->




<ARTICLE>

<TITLE>People Focus Diary</TITLE>

<SUBTITLE>Raipur (Chatthisgarh) and in Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh)</SUBTITLE>

<AUTHOR>Sunny Joseph</AUTHOR>

<SNIPPET>
In the year 2003, the People Focus leadership had taken a decision and later incorporated in its vision, to establish mission churches in Raipur (Chatthisgarh) and in Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh) in the next five years. Though much prayer went up nothing seemed to be happening and no doors were opening. However, we solaced ourselves thinking may be it’s not time yet. Chatthisgarh was formerly part of Madhya Pradesh in Central India, which was separated as an independent state by the Indian Government in the year 2000. Of the many north Indian states these two states have always been the back seat states for various reasons.
</SNIPPET>

<IMAGE>Chatthisgarh.jpg</IMAGE>

<FULL>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&quot; Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif&quot; &gt;
In the year 2003, the People Focus leadership had taken a decision and later incorporated in its vision, to establish mission churches in Raipur (Chatthisgarh) and in Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh) in the next five years. Though much prayer went up nothing seemed to be happening and no doors were opening. However, we solaced ourselves thinking may be it’s not time yet. Chatthisgarh was formerly part of Madhya Pradesh in Central India, which was separated as an independent state by the Indian Government in the year 2000. Of the many north Indian states these two states have always been the back seat states for various reasons. Of the 13% of the tribes in India, 8% live in these two states and the majority of them are in India’s largest district Bastar in southern Chatthisgarh. A district predominantly tribal. While the scheduled castes are 25,318 the scheduled tribes are 4,76,945. As a step towards fulfilling the vision written down in PF vision for 2003-2007, PF made its mission survey trip to Chatthisgarh from 7th – 10th of March 2006. (A prayer request was put up in the Altar of Prayer column of March- April 2006 issue of FoL requesting our readers to remember us in prayer during these days. Thank you so much if you have prayed for us.)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&quot; Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif&quot; &gt;
Though not many strong contacts were established on the mission survey trip to Chatthisgarh valuable information was gathered to begin with. It was a successful trip in many sorts.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&quot; Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif&quot; &gt; 
Our camp was in Raipur the capital city. Everyday morning much before the dawn one would hear unbelievable chants and the sound of cymbals for Hindu temples coming from almost every corner of the city. This is quite unlikely a sight and a rarity in many south Indian states, especially in the capital cities.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font face=&quot; Arial, Helvetica, sans-serif&quot; &gt;
The place is drenched in religious orthodoxy. There are quite a number of Churches but the membership is mostly of Christians who are from outside Chatthisgarh. Local Christian membership is thin. Please pray for People Focus and the team as we plan to actively share and spread the love of God.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</FULL>

</ARTICLE>