<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<FOLFEED>

<NEWS>
	<TITLE>India Today</TITLE>
	<SUBTITLE>The inside story of the atrocities on Christians in Orissa</SUBTITLE>
	<SNIPPET>This is the inside of India Today. We are hated in the land that we love where atrocities on Christian minority are a daily norm. If one travels through Kandhmal villages it 	would be hard to believe how could such a vast detestation be done in such a wide geographical area in such a short time and to such a depth that it would take a long time to restore 	what was destroyed. It is known to us and the nation too has witnessed that these attacks have been around for a long time. If Hindutva legitimates violence as patriotic response, 	one must wonder where this patriotism would lead to?</SNIPPET>
	<LINK>India Today.html</LINK>
	<IMAGE>India Today.jpg</IMAGE>	
</NEWS>
	
<NEWS>	
	<TITLE>Reaching Millions With Alpha</TITLE>
	<SUBTITLE>FoL with Rev. Nicky Gumbel</SUBTITLE>	
	<SNIPPET>
	SJ : Alpha has grown so much and is almost in 160 countries in the World.Is this where you expected it to be or is this something what you never expected when you first began with 		Alpha in 1991? 
	&lt;br&gt;
	NG : I am amazed to see the work of God particularly the different cultures and the way it has spread to different parts of the world. The way it spread into India where we reach 	people in many languages is absolutely amazing. It is fantastic.
	</SNIPPET>
	<LINK>NickyGumbelInterview.html</LINK>
	<IMAGE>Nicky.jpg</IMAGE>
</NEWS>

<NEWS>	
	<TITLE>People Focus Diary</TITLE>
	<SUBTITLE>Raipur (Chatthisgarh) and in Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh)</SUBTITLE>
	<SNIPPET>
In the year 2003, the People Focus leadership had taken a decision and later incorporated in its vision, to establish mission churches in Raipur (Chatthisgarh) and in Bhopal (Madhya Pradesh) in the next five years. Though much prayer went up nothing seemed to be happening and no doors were opening. However, we solaced ourselves thinking may be it’s not time yet. Chatthisgarh was formerly part of Madhya Pradesh in Central India, which was separated as an independent state by the Indian Government in the year 2000. Of the many north Indian states these two states have always been the back seat states for various reasons.
	</SNIPPET>
	<LINK>PFDiaryChatthisgarh.html</LINK>
	<IMAGE>Chatthisgarh.jpg</IMAGE>
</NEWS>
	
<NEWS>
	<TITLE>Fugitive for Christ </TITLE>
	<SUBTITLE>John Berlin (FMPB) with FoL</SUBTITLE>
	<SNIPPET>Police chase, arrest warrant, running, hiding, underground... SILENCE! 
	&lt;br&gt;
	...separated from wife and kids, what made a young man face such consequences when in good faith he stepped out for God to a mission field? A window to what goes on in the life of many missionaries in India...a true story!</SNIPPET>
	<LINK>FugitiveForChrist.html</LINK>
	<IMAGE>fugitive.jpg</IMAGE>
</NEWS>	
	

</FOLFEED>
